

London Ontario, Canada Github: github.com/olestourko

olestourko@gmail.com Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/olestourko

647-703-7906 Blog: olestourko.github.io

PROFILE SUMMARY

A versatile software developer with 4 years of professional experience and a background in Computer Science. I have a proven track record of completed professional and personal projects, and a strong drive for continuous education.

GENERAL: Object-Oriented Programming, Design Patterns, Unit Testing, Linux, Git, Machine Learning

LANGUAGES: Python, Java, PHP, Javascript, C#

BACKEND WEB: MVC, Laravel, Flask, SQLAlchemy, SQL, MongoDB, Apache, Nginx, Docker

FRONTEND WEB: ¡Query, AJAX, Knockout.js, ReactJS, HTML, SASS, CSS, Selenium

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer — Digital Extremes Inc, London Ontario

November 2015 — Present

A large game studio (300+ employees) best known for the title *Warframe*.

- Key contributor to and maintainer of our website (~450,000 unique daily visitors).
- Implemented a custom CMS database and backend with Laravel, and wrote scripts to port old content.
- Use Python and Google APIs to automate common tasks and web deployments.
- Work closely with other web developers, departments, and remote team members.
- Integrate with internal and third-party APIs.

Tech: Laravel, PHP, Python, MySQL, MongoDB, Javascript, SASS, Linux, Perforce, JIRA

Full Stack Web Developer — Northern Commerce Inc, London Ontario A digital agency specializing in ecommerce projects.

April 2014 - October 2015

- Full stack Magento development.
- Modified and integrated Magento extensions.
- Used Git for version control and participate in code reviews.
- Performed cross-browser frontend testing.

Tech: Magento, PHP, MySQL, Git, Javascript, CSS, Linux

SIDE PROJECTS

Software Developer (Python) — OpenPay London

February 2018 — Present

An open source salary sharing and comparison application for London, Ontario. I want to fix the problem of inadequate tech market data available in London.

Website: <u>londontechpay.ca</u> Source Code: <u>github.com/olestourko/open-tech-pay</u>

- Set core and secondary project goals, and launched a working core version.
- Built a completely decoupled frontend and RESTful backend.
- Deployment with Git and Docker on a VPS instance.
- Iterating based on feedback from the local developer community.

Tech: Python, Flask, Unittest, PostgreSQL, Marshmallow, Knockout.js, Docker, Git

Software Developer (Java) — SDBudget

February 2017 — August 2017

A personal budgeting and cashflow forecasting application. I wanted to build a budgeting tool based on my personal spreadsheet system, which works on the concept of a rolling surplus or deficit.

Website: <u>olestourko.github.io/sd-budget</u> Source Code: <u>github.com/olestourko/sd-budget</u>

- Planned the project and set intermediary development goals.
- Completed the application using Java, JavaFX, jOOQ, and H2 database.
- Used appropriate software design patterns to completely decouple the backend and frontend.
- Wrote an extensive unit testing suite using JUnit.
- Implemented website and created concise user documentation.

Tech: Java (SE8), JavaFX, jOOQ, H2 Database, JUnit, Git

EDUCATION

BSc. Computer Science - Ryerson University

2014

CERTIFICATIONS AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Machine Learning — Stanford University via Coursera
Parallel Programming in Java — Rice University via Coursera
LPIC-1 Linux System Administrator / Comptia Linux+
M101P: MongoDB for Developers

Completed August 2017 Completed October 2017 Completed February 2017 Completed December 2015